const e={sections:[{header:{text:"Transform the sentences into indirect speech."},exercises:[{type:"test",question:'The doctor said: "Stop drinking alcohol."',rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"The doctor asked to stop drinking alcohol.",2:"The doctor asked to stop drink alcohol.",3:"The doctor reminded that alcohol is bad."}},{type:"test",question:`"Let's do some reports on this subject," the student said.`,rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"The student offered to do some reports on this subject.",2:"The student offered not to do some reports on this subject.",3:"The student offered doing some reports on this subject."}},{type:"test",question:'Mother said: "Please, close the window."',rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Mother asked to close the window.",2:"Mother asked close the window please.",3:"Mother asked to close the window please."}},{type:"test",question:'"Find my glasses!" the grandmother said to Masha.',rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"The grandmother asked Masha to find her glasses.",2:"The grandmother asked Masha to find my glasses.",3:"The grandmother asked Masha to found her glasses."}},{type:"test",question:'"How about eating out tonight?" he said.',rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"He offered to eat out tonight.",2:"He asked about eating out tonight.",3:"He said to eat out tonight."}}]},{header:{text:"Translate into English using indirect commands"},exercises:[{type:"test",question:"Я попросила Динару дать мне словарь.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"I asked Dinara to give me a vocabulary.",2:"I asked Dinara if she gave me a vocabulary.",3:"Dinara, give me a vocabulary, asked I."}},{type:"test",question:"Учитель попросил студента стереть с доски.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"The teacher asked the student to clean the blackboard.",2:"The teacher asks the student to clean the blackboard.",3:"Clean the blackboard, asked the teacher."}},{type:"test",question:"Отец запретил сыну брать его машину.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Father forbidden his son to take his car.",2:"Father forbidden his son took his car.",3:"Father forbidden his car to be taken."}},{type:"test",question:"Мама попросила меня приготовить ужин.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Mother asked me to cook dinner.",2:"Mother asks me to cook dinner.",3:"Mother asked me not to cook dinner."}},{type:"test",question:"Он напомнил мне ответить на письмо.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"He reminded me to answer the letter.",2:"He reminded me answer the letter.",3:"He reminded me if answered the letter."}}]}]};export{e as default};
